The time of my reign has finally begun!
Excellent work, Miss Nobuna.
Do you understand your position?
Oh, are you going to kill me?
I'm your ruler now!
Not yet, you're not!
Leave her alone.
We finally got them to accept her succession.
If she gets killed, it'll all be for nothing.
And she makes a better figurehead if she's a bit dim.
I am the figurehead ruler!
A shiny, pretty figurehead.
The repairs to Yamato Palace are coming along well.
They should be finished in time for Imagawa's succession.
Sorry I've had to leave that to you when you're just back from battle.
Um, there's something that bothers me.
I don't know where Matsunaga Danjo is.
You don't think she ran with Miyoshi to Shikoku?
No.
But she can't do anything on her own.
I wouldn't think so, but...
What upsets me more is Mitsuhide!
Let it go already.
No!
Cheating is wrong.
Juubei was just too serious and stubborn about it.
Seems you really want to defend her.
That's not the issue here.
I know, already. She didn't mean anything wrong.
You're too naïve, Princess!
This is bad.
If she keeps getting isolated...
The more serious someone is,
the more likely they are to do something when they snap.
I have to stop the Honnouji event, no matter what.
Oda Nobuna no Yabou
The moment you swing the sword you pledged upon
You get hurt again
Biting down on my lip
I try to figure out what the right thing is
I will protect you, but before that
There's something I must do
I'm not trying to stand out
I just don't want to be a liar
I live on the battlefield with my life on the line
Whenever I look back, you're there to reassure me
The days of sorrow end, and the sun of ambition rises
Let's defeat fate and go as far as we want
Linking the world
Episode Nine
The Battle
at Kiyomizu Temple
Episode Nine
The Battle
at Kiyomizu Temple
Episode Nine
The Battle
at Kiyomizu Temple
Episode Nine
The Battle
at Kiyomizu Temple
Episode Nine
The Battle
at Kiyomizu Temple
Episode Nine
The Battle
at Kiyomizu Temple
Raise your head.
It was only a game.
But...
You overdid it a little, huh?
Shouldn't you apologize to Sagara?
I don't understand.
In a battle for promotion, there's no point if you don't win.
That's where you're wrong.
To the princess, her retainers are like family.
Does she want to see them fighting
each other and trying to put each other down?
The only family I have is my mother.
Family and retainers are different.
That's just because you were lucky.
You were loved by a wise mother.
Not hated as the princess was.
Isn't that just a rumor?
It's true.
Mother, I won!
I, Nobuna, protected Owari!
How dare you appear before your mother dressed in such wretched clothing?!
And you call yourself a princess of the Oda clan?!
Mother...
But she's so cheerful.
She wants to keep everyone from worrying, I'd imagine.
To her, you and Sagara are her family.
I...
What did you say?!
Takeda and Uesugi have stopped fighting over
Kawanakajima and made peace.
I don't believe it.
This is bad.
They must've decided that
with Nobuna in the capital, it wasn't time to fight.
They say that Takeda and Uesugi have joined forces.
And that they have 50,000 soldiers.
There's no time to lose.
Withdraw all of our forces to Gifu.
Wait, wait, wait!
Takeda and Uesugi can't join forces. It's impossible!
Well, it happened!
It is indeed true that they made peace in Kawanakajima.
What about Yamamoto Kansuke?
The Kitsutsuki Strategy failed, and Shingen's brother died, too, right?
Both Takeda's and Uesugi's armies are unharmed.
We've confirmed it.
What's going on?
Is history starting to drift away from what I know?
Because you saved me.
I was supposed to die at Magaragawa, too.
Did I do it?
Did I change history?
When I can't tell the future anymore,
can I still help her?
I'll have to believe in myself.
My soul as a Sengoku Era sim gamer is ringing alarm bells.
A Takeda-Uesugi army is impossible!
Don't turn back!
There's Owari and Mino between us and them.
We've made it to the capital
and are about to establish a new regime.
Everyone is seeing whether Oda Nobuna is fit to rule Japan.
All forces withdraw.
That's my decision.
There are people out there who believe in you.
That you'll be the one to create a new era.
Isn't this the time to stand firm?!
The Viper is...
in Mino.
My mother's in Owari.
I can't rule Japan if I abandon the people I care about.
I understand... I understand, but...
You don't understand.
You don't understand at all!
I never thought I'd hear you say that.
I thought that at least you would be different!
Nobuna...
I was supposed to send the person who
lost the takoyaki match to the Gifu Castle dungeons.
Princess!
Get out of here.
I don't want to see you ever again.
The main Oda force
began to turn back down the Eastern Sea Road
with Shibata Katsuie and Niwa Nagahide in the lead.
Leaving only Imagawa Yoshimoto and a small guard in Kyo.
The Fool Princess fell for it.
Now the area around Kyo is essentially abandoned.
It's Danjo's turn.
My forces are already lying in wait.
Make sure you don't kill Imagawa Yoshimoto.
I'll send her to you unharmed.
Akechi Mitsuhide is rather attractive herself.
The girl Tsuda is using, you mean?
I've got my eye on her as well.
All of the Oda girls are very beautiful.
When they join in,
my Tale of Genji will be all the more splendid.
Especially Oda Nobuna.
I won't let anyone else have her.
The Hikaru Genji of this age is very greedy.
I'll be on my way to Echizen, then.
Get to the capital as soon as you can, Yoshikage.
And I hope you can actually
get Takeda and Uesugi to do something next time, Advisor Konoe.
I know that!
Curse that perverted count!
All you'll get is Nobuna's corpse!
I thought at least you would be different!
I'm an idiot.
She's really just an ordinary girl.
A crybaby who wants her family to love her.
I should know that better than anyone.
And all I thought of was what Oda Nobuna the General should do.
I need to get a hold of myself.
I need to do more than just let her rule Japan.
Being a demon wouldn't suit her.
Wha—
Nobuna...
If you want to rule Japan,
isn't this the time to stand firm?
I know that, dummy.
Did you call me, Lord Nobuna?
Your forces are to stay and protect Kyo.
Yoshimoto's, too.
Lord Nobuna...
So, you do hate me.
She's about to declare her appointment.
We can't take her back with us.
And Monkey's right.
If we want to rule Japan,
we can't abandon Kyo, no matter what.
Defend it with your life until I get back.
All right.
Hey, have you seen Monkey?
Well...
What's wrong?
Yoshiharu's been kidnapped.
Kidnapped?
Someone saw somebody carrying what looked like Mr. Yoshiharu.
No...
What the hell?!
Who are you?
Why did you kidnap me?
As bait.
You're bait to bring in Oda Nobuna.
You plan to assassinate her? Who put you up to this?
Stay put.
Once the target's dead, I'll kill you, too.
Nobuna won't come out here—
I don't know about that.
Lord Nobuna has left.
I see.
I'm all alone here.
All I can do now is the job I've been given.
I, Akechi Juubei Mitsuhide, shall protect Kyo!
Goemon, where's Monkey?
Someone said they saw him on the way to Oumi!
Stay safe, Monkey.
I haven't apologized to you yet.
We'll pay you three times what you're getting.
I'd rather have fame than money.
If I kill Oda Nobuna, the one on the verge of uniting Japan,
I, Sugitani Zenjuubou, shall be famous throughout the land.
Screw you!
If she dies, it'll take 100 more years to unite Japan!
Fine by me.
If Japan is united and at peace, people like me are out of a job.
People who, like me, love this chaotic civil war age.
Meanwhile, Oda's main forces were heading to south Oumi.
Takeda and Uesugi aren't doing anything?
It's true that they made peace at Kawanakajima.
The rest of it is all lies, I believe.
No...
A trap to draw Oda's forces away from Kyo.
Matsunaga's forces number 3000.
I believe they're going after Yoshimoto.
When did they get here?
Our forces number 800.
What shall we do?
We'll have to make them siege us.
This is a temple!
We just need to buy time until Lord Nobuna gets back.
Close all the doors and focus on defense!
Miss Mitsuhide!
I'm counting on you!
Mother, the only good thing is that Lord Nobuna left this place.
They say that a person's smile
is most beautiful when they've accepted death.
Who are you?!
Matsunaga Danjo Hisahide.
What's an enemy general doing here?
I wanted to kill a beautiful girl like you myself.
My spear techniques are of the Houzouin-style.
Oda Nobuna's retainer, Akechi Juubei Mitsuhide:
a master of the Kashima Shintou-Style.
It's almost time.
Damn it! Because of me, Nobuna...
That's it!
Monkey's up there?
Someone like you could have Japan for yourself.
Why are you just one of Oda Nobuna's retainers?
She's the one who is fit to rule Japan.
I've bet my dreams on her!
Dreams are a fragile thing.
I'm not going to stand here talking to you all day.
Beautiful, intelligent, noble,
with a burning dream...
Whenever I meet someone like you,
I can't help myself...
I just want to kill you.
The despair on your face when your dream falls apart...
I want to see it.
Come, the stage is prepared.
Let us kill each other.
Stay back. Stay away!
Isn't there anything I can do?
If it turns on for even an instant...
Save Nobuna for me!
I guess I underestimated you.
Sweet dreams.
I won't lose to an illusion!
You're wonderful!
But what if, after all this effort,
your beloved Lord Nobuna was already dead?
Somebody hired an assassin.
She's probably been shot by now.
No...
Lord Nobuna's dead?
Dead...
Once there's an opening into their heart,
people are so fragile.
Snap out of it, Juubei!
Lord Nobuna?
You're alive.
Of course I am!
Lord Nobuna!
What are you doing here?
Saved at the last second.
Sugitani Zenjuubou escaped, though.
And so we ran back here.
Even with just the five of us,
we're more than enough reinforcement!
Are you stupid?
If something happens to Lord Nobuna...
She made that decision herself.
Juubei can be a little close-minded,
but she's part of my family, and shares my dream.
She said that?
It's a dream.
Just a dream.
So, it is a dream.
It's no dream!
Monkey Man!
Stay out of this!
Monkey, are you okay?
You'll pay for what you did to Mr. Yoshiharu.
Why did you save me?
Why can't you believe in Nobuna?!
But I...
She needs you!
If you ever find yourself uncertain in the future, remember...
the image of Kiyomizu Temple burning,
and how Nobuna appeared!
Mr. Sagara.
The tables have turned, Matsunaga Danjo.
Unfortunate.
I'd hoped to bring even greater chaos to these times of war.
So, you're just like that assassin?
No.
My wish is to burn this whole country to the ground.
Why would you...
If I told you the answer was my skin,
would you understand?
How long can just five of you fight?
There's more than just the five of us.
The "Bontenmaru Wants to Be Like That Too Super-Sword!"
The beast of the apocalypse, Bontenmaru, is here!
Takayama Dom Justo shall aide you!
Konishi Joachin is here as well!
Everyone here is your ally in creating a new era!
Those are all people like me,
hated and with no place in this country.
Even missionaries with no weapons.
This is Oda Nobuna's power?
She's different...
She's different from everyone else.
I'm certain she can...
I, Matsunaga Danjo Hisahide, surrender myself.
I see.
Several days later,
Imagawa Yoshimoto was officially appointed to her new position.
A new order and governing power were established,
and Nobuna took another step towards conquering Japan.
I want to have Oda Nobuna rule the country.
Only when it has a good ruler
can the nation have a brighter future.
Lady Himeko.
Nobuna is a country count who loves war.
We don't know what she may be thinking.
It's true that I don't know what's in her heart.
But the man behind her,
Sagara Yoshiharu, is a good man.
D-Did this monkey touch you?
What is she talking about?
Just by touching someone, she can read what's in their heart.
Seriously?!
If Sagara Yoshiharu's feelings burn so brightly for her,
Oda Nobuna must be a good person as well.
Lady Himeko!
But Yoshiharu likes girls.
His head was filled with images of them.
Oda Nobuna, take care.
I'll remember that.
Oda Nobuna...
why didn't you lead the new regime yourself?
I'll pass on that.
What I want is freedom.
Freedom?
I want to remove the idea of "position" from this country,
and show, through my own life,
that you can choose your own future.
You blaspheme—
I understand.
But why do you feel that way?
For my dreams!
I will pray that your dreams come true.
tada jidai no mannaka tatasarete tomadou toki ni
When I, lost in time, was standing there confused
te wo hiite kureta hito e dekiru koto sagashita
You pulled me through, so I wanted to do something in return
kizutsuki nagara warau sugata
You were smiling even though you were being hurt
kokoro no ura namida ga mieta
I saw you shedding tears deep inside
sukui motomeru koe kikitoreru no wa
I could only understand your call for help
yurusareta mono dake
When you opened up to me
kazoe kirenu arashi wo koete
I will overcome the countless storms
anata no yami saku hikari ni naru
And become the light that cuts through your darkness
mou mayowanai tomo ni ikitai
I won't hesitate anymore; let's go together
chikau yume ga donna mubou de atte mo
No matter how unrealistic our ambitions are
oboeteite shinjirareru basho wa
Remember there's a place you can believe in
koko ni aru to
Right here
Episode Ten
Nobuna in Grave Danger